Emeka Onyedika

MERN Stack and Blockchain Programmer.

Location: Nigeria

Email: chuksremi15@gmail.com Phone: +2348160564759

Github: https://github.com/chuksremi15 Portfolio: https://chuksremyblog.web.app/ Linkedin: click to redirect to linkedin

Full-stack and blockchain programmer with over 5 years of experience. Solid skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux, Node.js, Solidity, Rust. Experienced project team lead. Willing to learn and improve along with conventions in the ecosystem. Graduate of Computer Science.

Technical Skills

Node.js React Solidity Typescript Redux MongoDB Next.js Rust

Additional skills:

Blockchain Hardhat Truffle Docker Foundry Ethers Firebase

Express.js

TailwindCss MongoDB

Work History

Blockchain programmer at Clynto | USA September 2024 - March | 7 months

clynto.com

lend and borrow crypto assets on EVM compatible blockchain using a peer-to-peer model Developed and deployed a proxy-based smart contract to implement

Clynto is an on-chain lending and borrowing protocol that allows users to

- Clynto's lending and borrowing model. Wrote comprehensive unit tests for the smart contract, hooks, and end-to-
- end (E2E) workflows Utilized Solidity, TypeScript, Hardhat, Viem, Wagmi, React Query, and
- Playwright for development and testing.

October 2023 - May 2024 | 8 months

Blockchain programmer at BuidlGuidl USA

BuidlGuidl porfolio

BuidlGuidl is a decentralized autonomous organization acting as the community and incentivization layer around scaffold-eth and

speedrunethereum.com Built and shipped buildlguidl challenge problems and personal blockchain projects.

- Utilized Solidity, Typescript, Hardhat, Viem, Wagmi, React-query.

https://aimovement.tech/

MERN stack dev at Al Movement | Nigeria

Al Movement is a community of private investors, institutional investors,

September 2022 - December 2023 | 1 year 4 months

small team of one frontend programmer and a UI/UX person.

 Responsible for the full cycles of the application development which include writing code, writing tests, and inspecting all code base.

and technology experts. I worked as the CTO at Al Movement, with a

- Drawing out system architecture/blueprints for projects. Ensuring smooth functionality of our app and fixing bugs
- Worked with React, Redux, Express.js, Node.js.

Full-stack Blockchain Programmer at Omitch | Nigeria

January 2022 - June 2022 | 6 months Webapp: https://omitchapp.web.app/

Omitch is a casino start-up that integrated web2 games and handle payments with web3 Responsible for the full cycles of the blockchain development which include

Converted casino business logic to code.

December 2020 - December 2021 | 1 year

Integrated API's to frontend Applications.

Website: https://omitchgames.web.app/

 Integrated games from a gaming provider Worked with Hardhat, Mocha, Chai, Ethers, and Web3js.

writing smart contracts, writing tests, and integrating ABIs to frontend.

Frontend Programmer at Canary Tech | Nigeria

This project didn't take off due to the teams inability to raise fund as a

consequence the game providers have disconnected access.

Canary tech is the parent company of parapay, a fintech startup. • Collaborated with a team of two developers in building the admin section of the

• Worked with Chakra UI, Sass, Redux-saga. Developed Admin front end using react and redux-saga for state management

The product has handled more than 1 billion naira in transactions

Coinbox

Frenfinance https://frenfinance.xyz/

and Lending

Projects

fintech app.

support for low- to mid-cap tokens with healthy liquidity

https://www.lyxaxis.xyz/

https://coinbox.vercel.app/

Lyxaxis

Lyxaxis is a multi-signature wallet with support for universal business profiles on

FrenFinance is an on-chain lending and borrowing platform designed to include

Coinbox is a Unified Wallet-Native Platform for Swapping, Onramping, Offramping,

Lukso chain

Chain link CLI(NPM package) https://www.npmjs.com/package/chainpeekcli Blockchain CLI that gives you easy access to blockchain data from your command

Rust GREP(globally search a regular expression and print) CLI https://github.com/Chuksremi15/rust_cli_minigrep

line and for deploying single file smart contract.

project is a simplified version of the Unix grep command, built as an exercise while learning Rust.

A command-line tool for searching for patterns in files, implemented in Rust. This

Education

December 2017 - December 2021 Nnamdi Azikiwe University

BSC in computer science